Guide to the New-York Historical Society Geographic Images Collection circa 1600-2006 PR 20
New-York Historical Society
- Series I: New York City Views - Manhattan
  - Subseries IA: MANHATTAN - BOXED MATERIAL
    - Manhattan - Boxed Material - Buildings
      - Buildings-Commercial & Financial-Stores & Shops-General (Box 61, Folder 15)
      - Buildings-Commercial & Financial-Stores & Shops-Art Galleries and Auction Houses (Box 62, Folder 1)
      - Buildings-Commercial & Financial-Stores & Shops-Booksellers (Box 62, Folder 2)
      - Buildings-Commercial & Financial-Stores & Shops-Clothing and Accessory Stores (Box 62, Folder 3)
      - Buildings-Commercial & Financial-Stores & Shops-Department Stores-General (Box 62, Folder 4)
      - Buildings-Commercial & Financial-Stores & Shops-Department Stores- A.T. Stewart (Box 62, Folder 5)
      - Buildings-Commercial & Financial-Stores & Shops-Department Stores- Lord & Taylor (Box 62, Folder 6)
      - Buildings-Commercial & Financial-Stores & Shops-Drugstores and Opticians (Box 62, Folder 7)
      - Buildings-Commercial & Financial-Stores & Shops-Dry Goods (Box 62, Folder 8)
      - Buildings-Commercial & Financial-Stores & Shops-Florists and Nurseries (Box 62, Folder 9)
      - Buildings-Commercial & Financial-Stores & Shops-Food, Beverage, and Tobacco shops (Box 62, Folder 10)
      - Buildings-Commercial & Financial-Stores & Shops-Jewelers-General (Box 62, Folder 11)
      - Buildings-Commercial & Financial-Stores & Shops-Jewelers- Tiffany and Company, various locations (Box 62, Folder 12)
      - Buildings-Commercial & Financial-Stores & Shops-Photographic Studios (Box 62, Folder 13)
      - Buildings-Government-General (Box 63, Folder 1)
      - Buildings-Government-Castle Garden, 1855-90: Immigrant Station (Box 63, Folder 2)
      - Buildings-Government-City Hall, Dutch (Stadt Huys), Pearl Street (Box 63, Folder 3)
      - Buildings-Government-City Hall, Wall Street (Federal Hall) (Box 63, Folder 4)
      - Buildings-Government-City Hall (Box 63, Folder 5-8)
      - Buildings-Government-City Hall (Margot Gayle Donation) (Box 63, Folder 9)
      - Buildings-Government-Courts (General) (Box 63, Folder 10)
      - Buildings-Government-Courts-Criminal Courts Building, Centre St. (Box 64, Folder 1)
      - Buildings-Government-Courts-City and Municipal Courts Building, Centre and White Sts. (Box 64, Folder 2)
      - Buildings-Government-Courts-Tweed Court House (Box 64, Folder 3)
      - Buildings-Government-Custom House, Wall Street (Box 64, Folder 4)
      - Buildings-Government-Custom House, Bowling Green (Box 64, Folder 5)
      - Buildings-Government-Fire Departments and Fire Houses (Box 64, Folder 6)
      - Buildings-Government-Government House, Bowling Green (Box 64, Folder 7)
      - Buildings-Government-Hall of Records, City Hall Park (Box 64, Folder 8)
      - Buildings-Government-Hall of Records, Chambers St. (Box 64, Folder 9)
      - Buildings-Government-Municipal Building (Box 64, Folder 10)
      - Buildings-Government-Police Department and Police Precints (Box 64, Folder 11)
      - Buildings-Government-Post Offices-General (Box 65, Folder 1)
      - Buildings-Government-Post Offices-Broadway and Park Row (Box 65, Folder 2)
      - Buildings-Government-Post Offices-Nassau St. (Box 65, Folder 3)
      - Buildings-Government-Prisons-General (Box 65, Folder 4)
      - Buildings-Government-Prisons-"Newgate" State Prison, Greenwich Village (1796-1828) (Box 65, Folder 5)
      - Buildings-Government-Prisons-"The Tombs," City Prison folder 1 of 2) (Box 65, Folder 6-7)
      - Buildings-Government-Public Bath (Box 65, Folder 8)
      - Buildings-Gymnasiums (Box 65, Folder 9)
      - Buildings-Hotels-A miscellaneous (Box 65, Folder 10)
      - Buildings-Hotels-Abbey Hotel (Box 65, Folder 11)
      - Buildings-Hotels-Albermarle (Box 65, Folder 12)
      - Buildings-Hotels-Astor House, Broadway and Vesey St. (Box 65, Folder 13)
      - Buildings-Hotels-B miscellaneous (Box 66, Folder 1)
      - Buildings-Hotels-C miscellaneous (Box 66, Folder 2)
      - Buildings-Hotels-City Hotel (Box 66, Folder 3)
      - Buildings-Hotels-Claremont Hotel (Box 66, Folder 4)
      - Buildings-Hotels-Clinton Hotel (Box 66, Folder 5)
      - Buildings-Hotels-Collamore House (Box 66, Folder 6)
      - Buildings-Hotels-D miscellaneous (Box 66, Folder 7)
      - Buildings-Hotels-Delmonico's (26th street, Broadway, and Fifth Avenue) (Box 66, Folder 8)
      - Buildings-Hotels-Delmonico's (Other locations) (Box 66, Folder 9)
      - Buildings-Hotels-E miscellaneous (Box 66, Folder 10)
      - Buildings-Hotels-Everett House (Box 66, Folder 11)
      - Buildings-Hotels-F miscellaneous (Box 66, Folder 12)
      - Buildings-Hotels-Fifth Avenue Hotel (Box 66, Folder 13)
      - Buildings-Hotels-G miscellaneous (Box 66, Folder 14)
      - Buildings-Hotels-Gilsey House (Box 66, Folder 15)
      - Buildings-Hotels-(Old) Gotham Inn (Box 66, Folder 16)
      - Buildings-Hotels-Grand Hotel (Box 66, Folder 17)
      - Buildings-Hotels-Grand Central Hotel (Box 66, Folder 18)
      - Buildings-Hotels-Grand Union Hotel (interior) (Box 67, Folder 1)
      - Buildings-Hotels-Grand Union Hotel (art collection) (Box 67, Folder 2)
      - Buildings-Hotels-H miscellaneous (Box 67, Folder 3)
      - Buildings-Hotels-Hoffman House (Box 67, Folder 4)
      - Buildings-Hotels-Holt's Hotel (Box 67, Folder 5)
      - Buildings-Hotels-I miscellaneous (Box 67, Folder 6)
      - Buildings-Hotels-J miscellaneous (Box 67, Folder 7)
      - Buildings-Hotels-K miscellaneous (Box 67, Folder 8)
      - Buildings-Hotels-L miscellaneous (Box 67, Folder 9)
      - Buildings-Hotels-La Farge House (Box 67, Folder 10)
      - Buildings-Hotels-M miscellaneous (Box 67, Folder 11)
      - Buildings-Hotels-Madison Cottage (Box 67, Folder 14)
      - Buildings-Hotels-Hotel Majestic (Box 67, Folder 13)
      - Buildings-Hotels-Mansion House (Box 67, Folder 14)
      - Buildings-Hotels-Metropolitan Hotel (Box 67, Folder 15)
      - Buildings-Hotels-Murray Hill Hotel (Box 68, Folder 1)
      - Buildings-Hotels-N miscellaneous (Box 68, Folder 2)
      - Buildings-Hotels-O miscellaneous (Box 68, Folder 3)
      - Buildings-Hotels-P miscellaneous (Box 68, Folder 4)
      - Buildings-Hotels-Park Avenue Hotel (Box 68, Folder 5)
      - Buildings-Hotels-Plaza Hotel (Box 68, Folder 6)
      - Buildings-Hotels-R miscellaneous (Box 68, Folder 7)
      - Buildings-Hotels-Rathbun's Hotel (Box 68, Folder 8)
      - Buildings-Hotels-S miscellaneous (Box 68, Folder 9)
      - Buildings-Hotels-Saint James Hotel (Box 68, Folder 10)
      - Buildings-Hotels-Saint Nicholas Hotel (Box 68, Folder 11)
      - Buildings-Hotels-Savoy Hotel (Box 68, Folder 12)
      - Buildings-Hotels-Sturtevant House (Box 68, Folder 13)
      - Buildings-Hotels-T miscellaneous (Box 68, Folder 14)
      - Buildings-Hotels-U miscellaneous (Box 69, Folder 1)
      - Buildings-Hotels-V miscellaneous (Box 69, Folder 2)
      - Buildings-Hotels-Hotel Vendome (Box 69, Folder 3)
      - Buildings-Hotels-W miscellaneous (Box 69, Folder 4)
      - Buildings-Hotels-Waldorf Astoria (Box 69, Folder 5)
      - Buildings-Hotels-Washington (Hall) Hotel (Box 69, Folder 6)
      - Buildings-Hotels-Windsor Hotel (Box 69, Folder 7)
      - Buildings-Hotels-miscellaneous (Box 69, Folder 8)
      - Buildings-Institutions-Asylums, Homes, & Social Services-General (Box 69, Folder 9)
      - Buildings-Institutions-Asylums, Homes, & Social Services-African-American (Box 69, Folder 10)
      - Buildings-Institutions-Asylums, Homes, & Social Services-Female (Box 69, Folder 11)
      - Buildings-Institutions-Asylums, Homes, & Social Services-Orphan Asylums-Hebrew Orphan Asylum (Box 69, Folder 12)
      - Buildings-Institutions-Asylums, Homes, & Social Services-Orphan Asylums-Leake and Watts Orphanage and School (Box 69, Folder 13)
      - Buildings-Institutions-Asylums, Homes, & Social Services-Orphan Asylums-New York Juvenile Asylum (Box 69, Folder 14)
      - Buildings-Institutions-Asylums, Homes, & Social Services-Orphan Asylums-New York Orphan Asylum (Box 69, Folder 15)
      - Buildings-Institutions-Asylums, Homes, & Social Services-Orphan Asylums-Roman Catholic Orphan Asylums (Box 69, Folder 16)
      - Buildings-Institutions-Asylums, Homes, & Social Services-Bloomingdale Insane Asylum (Box 69, Folder 17)
      - Buildings-Institutions-Asylums, Homes, & Social Services-Five Points Mission and Five Points House of Industry (Box 69, Folder 18)
      - Buildings-Institutions-Asylums, Homes, & Social Services-House of Refuge (Box 70, Folder 1)
      - Buildings-Institutions-Asylums, Homes, & Social Services-New York Institution for the Blind (Box 70, Folder 2)
      - Buildings-Institutions-Asylums, Homes, & Social Services-New York Institution of the Instruction of the Deaf (Box 70, Folder 3)
      - Buildings-Institutions-Hospitals-A-Z General (Box 70, Folder 4)
      - Buildings-Institutions-Hospitals-Dispensaries (Box 70, Folder 5)
      - Buildings-Institutions-Hospitals-Bellevue (Box 70, Folder 6)
      - Buildings-Institutions-Hospitals-Flower Hospital (Box 70, Folder 7)
      - Buildings-Institutions-Hospitals-Harlem Hospital (Box 70, Folder 8)
      - Buildings-Institutions-Hospitals-Mount Sinai Hospital (Box 70, Folder 9)
      - Buildings-Institutions-Hospitals-New York Hospital (Box 70, Folder 10)
      - Buildings-Institutions-Hospitals-Presbyterian Hospital (Box 70, Folder 11)
      - Buildings-Institutions-Hospitals-Roosevelt Hospital (Box 70, Folder 12)
      - Buildings-Institutions-Hospitals-St. Luke's Hospital (Box 70, Folder 13)
      - Buildings-Libraries-A-Z General (Box 70, Folder 14)
      - Buildings-Libraries-Astor Library (Box 70, Folder 15)
      - Buildings-Libraries-Colman's Literary Rooms (Box 70, Folder 16)
      - Buildings-Libraries-Lenox Library (Box 70, Folder 17)
      - Buildings-Libraries-Mercantile Library (Box 70, Folder 18)
      - Buildings-Libraries-New York Public Library- Research Library, Main Library (42nd st. and fifth avenue) (Box 71, Folder 1)
      - Buildings-Libraries-New York Public Library-Branch libraries (Box 71, Folder 2)
      - Buildings-Libraries-New York Society Library (Box 71, Folder 3)
      - Buildings-Museums-A-Z miscellaneous (Box 71, Folder 4)
      - Buildings-Museums-Aquariums (Box 71, Folder 5)
      - Buildings-Museums-American Museum of Natural History (Box 71, Folder 6)
      - Buildings-Museums-Barnum's American Museum (and predecessors) (Box 71, Folder 7)
      - Buildings-Museums-Cloisters (Box 71, Folder 8)
      - Buildings-Museums-Metropolitan Museum of Art (Box 71, Folder 9)
      - Buildings-Museums-Museum of the City of New York (Box 71, Folder 10)
      - Buildings-Museums-New-York Historical Society (Box 71, Folder 11)
      - Buildings-Manufacturies & Warehouses-A-Z miscellaneous (Box 71, Folder 12)
      - Buildings-Manufacturies & Warehouses-Beverage manufacturers (including distilleries and breweries) (Box 72, Folder 1)
      - Buildings-Manufacturies & Warehouses-Coach and Carriage manufacturers (Box 72, Folder 2)
      - Buildings-Manufacturies & Warehouses-Ironworks (Box 72, Folder 3)
      - Buildings-Manufacturies & Warehouses-Piano manufacturers and factories-General (Box 72, Folder 4)
      - Buildings-Manufacturies & Warehouses-Piano manufacturers and factories-Steinway (Box 72, Folder 5)
      - Buildings-Manufacturies & Warehouses-Sugar refineries and manufacturers (Box 72, Folder 6)
      - Buildings-Monuments & Statuary-A-G general (Box 72, Folder 7)
      - Buildings-Monuments & Statuary-Columbus Monument, Columbus Circle (Box 72, Folder 8)
      - Buildings-Monuments & Statuary-Dewey Arch (Box 72, Folder 9)
      - Buildings-Monuments & Statuary-Grant's Tomb (Box 72, Folder 10)
      - Buildings-Monuments & Statuary-H-M general (Box 72, Folder 11)
      - Buildings-Monuments & Statuary-N-Z general (Box 72, Folder 12)
      - Buildings-Monuments & Statuary-Sherman Monument (Box 73, Folder 1)
      - Buildings-Monuments & Statuary-Sailors and Soldiers Monument (Box 73, Folder 2)
      - Buildings-Monuments & Statuary-U.S.S. Maine Monument (Box 73, Folder 3)
      - Buildings-Monuments & Statuary-Victory Arch, 1919, Madison Square (Box 73, Folder 4)
      - Buildings-Monuments & Statuary-Washington, George (various statues) (Box 73, Folder 5)
      - Buildings-Monuments & Statuary-Washington Arch (Box 73, Folder 6)
      - Buildings-Monuments & Statuary-X, Y, Z & Miscellaneous (Box 73, Folder 7)
      - Buildings-Printing, Publishing & Newspapers-Publishers and Printers (Box 73, Folder 8)
      - Buildings-Printing, Publishing & Newspapers-General (Box 73, Folder 9)
      - Buildings-Printing, Publishing & Newspapers-New York Daily News (incl. Spanish-Amer. War Crowd dispatches) (Box 73, Folder 10)
      - Buildings-Printing, Publishing & Newspapers-New York Herald (Box 73, Folder 11)
      - Buildings-Printing, Publishing & Newspapers-New York Times (early) (Box 73, Folder 12)
      - Buildings-Printing, Publishing & Newspapers-New York Times (Box 73, Folder 13)
      - Buildings-Printing, Publishing & Newspapers-Pulitzer/World Building (Box 73, Folder 14)
      - Buildings-Printing, Publishing & Newspapers-Tribune Building (Box 73, Folder 15)
      - Buildings-Printing, Publishing & Newspapers-Staats Zeitung (Box 73, Folder 16)
      - Buildings-Residences-A miscellaneous (Box 74, Folder 1)
      - Buildings-Residences-Adams, John (See Richmond Hill)
      - Buildings-Residences-Alwyn Court (Box 74, Folder 2)
      - Buildings-Residences-Ansonia (Box 74, Folder 3)
      - Buildings-Residences-Apthorpe Mansion, W. 91st street and Ninth Ave (Box 74, Folder 4)
      - Buildings-Residences-Astor family residences (Box 74, Folder 5)
      - Buildings-Residences-Audubon, John James, residence (Box 74, Folder 6)
      - Buildings-Residences-B miscellaneous (Box 74, Folder 7)
      - Buildings-Residences-Beekman family residences (Box 74, Folder 8)
      - Buildings-Residences-Blumenthal, George and Florence (Box 74, Folder 9)
      - Buildings-Residences-Bradhurst family, "Pinehurst" (Box 74, Folder 10)
      - Buildings-Residences-Brevoort Houses (Box 74, Folder 11)
      - Buildings-Residences-Burr, Aaron (See Richmond Hill)
      - Buildings-Residences-Bussing House (Box 74, Folder 12)
      - Buildings-Residences-C miscellaneous (Box 74, Folder 13)
      - Buildings-Residences-Clark, Cyrus, residence, Riverside Drive at 90th street (Box 74, Folder 14)
      - Buildings-Residences-Coster House, 30th street and First Ave (Box 74, Folder 15)
      - Buildings-Residences-Cromwell Residence, 12 W. 49th street (Box 74, Folder 16)
      - Buildings-Residences-Crosby, William B., residence (See Rutgers/Crosby House)
      - Buildings-Residences-D miscellaneous (Box 75, Folder 1)
      - Buildings-Residences-Dakota Apartments, Central Park West at 72nd St. (Box 75, Folder 2)
      - Buildings-Residences-De Peyster residence (Box 75, Folder 3)
      - Buildings-Residences-Donnelly Residence, "Grove Mount", 135th st. between Broadway & Amsterdam Ave. (Box 75, Folder 4)
      - Buildings-Residences-Dyckman House (Box 75, Folder 5)
      - Buildings-Residences-E miscellaneous (Box 75, Folder 6)
      - Buildings-Residences-F miscellaneous (Box 75, Folder 7)
      - Buildings-Residences-Field, Marshall, residence (Box 75, Folder 8)
      - Buildings-Residences-Fish family residence (Box 75, Folder 9)
      - Buildings-Residences-Fitch, Clyde, residence (Box 75, Folder 10)
      - Buildings-Residences-Flagg, Ernest, residence (Box 75, Folder 11)
      - Buildings-Residences-Franklin Residence (Box 75, Folder 12)
      - Buildings-Residences-G miscellaneous (Box 75, Folder 13)
      - Buildings-Residences-Goelet, Peter, residence, Broadway and 19th st. (Box 75, Folder 14)
      - Buildings-Residences-Gracie Mansion (Box 76, Folder 1-2)
      - Buildings-Residences-Gregory, John, residence (Box 76, Folder 3)
      - Buildings-Residences-Grenzebach Estate (Box 76, Folder 4)
        General
        alternate spelling "Grenseback"
      - Buildings-Residences-H miscellaneous (Box 76, Folder 5)
      - Buildings-Residences-Hamilton Grange (prints) (Box 76, Folder 6)
      - Buildings-Residences-Hamilton Grange (photos) (Box 76, Folder 7)
      - Buildings-Residences-Havemeyer family residences (Box 76, Folder 8)
      - Buildings-Residences-Hopper Farm (Box 76, Folder 9)
      - Buildings-Residences-I-J miscellaneous (Box 76, Folder 10)
      - Buildings-Residences-Jumel Mansion (Box 76, Folder 11)
      - Buildings-Residences-K miscellaneous (Box 76, Folder 12)
      - Buildings-Residences-L miscellaneous (Box 77, Folder 1)
      - Buildings-Residences-Livingston family residences (Box 77, Folder 2)
      - Buildings-Residences-M miscellaneous (Box 77, Folder 3)
      - Buildings-Residences-Moore, Bishop Benjamin, residence (Clement Clark Moore Estate) (Box 77, Folder 4)
      - Buildings-Residences-Morris, Roger residence (See: Jumel Mansion)
      - Buildings-Residences-Morris, Lewis Gouvernor, residence, Madison Avenue (1913) (Box 77, Folder 5)
      - Buildings-Residences-Morris Residence, Madison Avenue (1915) (Box 77, Folder 6)
      - Buildings-Residences-N miscellaneous (Box 77, Folder 7)
      - Buildings-Residences-O miscellaneous (Box 77, Folder 8)
      - Buildings-Residences-P-Q miscellaneous (Box 77, Folder 9)
      - Buildings-Residences-Pinkney, Mary G. residence, 139 W. 139th street (Box 77, Folder 10)
      - Buildings-Residences-Pyne House, Percy, 68th street and Park Avenue (Box 77, Folder 11)
      - Buildings-Residences-R miscellaneous (Box 77, Folder 12)
      - Buildings-Residences-Richmond Hill (Box 77, Folder 13)
      - Buildings-Residences-Rudd Mansion, Riversider Dr. and W. 114th street (Box 77, Folder 14)
      - Buildings-Residences-Rutgers-Crosby residence (Box 77, Folder 15)
      - Buildings-Residences-S miscellaneous (Box 78, Folder 1)
      - Buildings-Residences-Samler, Casper, residence, 29th St. and Broadway (Box 78, Folder 2)
      - Buildings-Residences-Schermerhorn family residences (Box 78, Folder 3)
      - Buildings-Residences-Schuyler residence (Box 78, Folder 4)
      - Buildings-Residences-Schwab, Charles S., residence, Riverside Dr. and 73rd street (Box 78, Folder 5)
      - Buildings-Residences-Smith, Abigail Adams, residence, 421 E. 61st street (Box 78, Folder 6)
      - Buildings-Residences-Stewart, A.T., residence (Box 78, Folder 7)
      - Buildings-Residences-Stilwell, Dr. John D., residence, 9 W. 49th street (Box 78, Folder 8)
      - Buildings-Residences-Stuyvesant, Augustus Van Horne, residence, 975 Fifth Ave (Box 78, Folder 9)
      - Buildings-Residences-Stuyvesant family residence (Box 78, Folder 10)
      - Buildings-Residences-Sulzer, William, residence, 119 Washington Place (Box 78, Folder 11)
      - Buildings-Residences-T-U Miscellaneous (Box 79, Folder 1)
      - Buildings-Residences-Tiffany residence (Box 79, Folder 2)
      - Buildings-Residences-V miscellaneous (Box 79, Folder 3)
      - Buildings-Residences-Vanderbilt family residences (Box 79, Folder 4)
      - Buildings-Residences-Van Nest family residences (Box 79, Folder 5)
      - Buildings-Residences-W miscellaneous (Box 79, Folder 6)
      - Buildings-Residences-Waddell residence (Box 79, Folder 7)
      - Buildings-Residences-Walton residence (Box 79, Folder 8)
      - Buildings-Residences-Wilson, Orme, residence (Box 79, Folder 9)
      - Buildings-Residences-X-Z miscellaneous (Box 79, Folder 10)
      - Buildings-Residences-Unidentified miscellaneous (Box 79, Folder 11)
      - Buildings-Residences-Apartment Houses, including roof gardens (Box 80, Folder 1)
      - Buildings-Residences-Public Housing Projects (Box 80, Folder 2)
      - Buildings-Restaurants & Taverns-Coffee Houses A-Z (Box 80, Folder 3)
      - Buildings-Restaurants & Taverns-Coffee Houses- Burns/Atlantic Garden/Kings Arms Tavern (Box 80, Folder 4)
      - Buildings-Restaurants & Taverns-Restaurants A-Z (Box 80, Folder 5)
      - Buildings-Restaurants & Taverns-Windows on the World (Box 80, Folder 6)
      - Buildings-Restaurants & Taverns-Restaurants- Unidentified (Box 80, Folder 7)
      - Buildings-Restaurants & Taverns-Taverns A-Z (Box 80, Folder 8)
      - Buildings-Restaurants & Taverns-Brodie's (Box 80, Folder 9)
      - Buildings-Restaurants & Taverns-Buck Horn (Box 80, Folder 10)
      - Buildings-Restaurants & Taverns-Bull's Head (Box 80, Folder 11)
      - Buildings-Restaurants & Taverns-Fraunces Tavern (Box 80, Folder 12)
      - Buildings-Restaurants & Taverns-Unidentified taverns (Box 80, Folder 13)
      - Buildings-Schools & Colleges-New York City Public Schools- Named Schools (Box 81, Folder 1)
      - Buildings-Schools & Colleges-New York City Public Schools- Numbered schools (Box 81, Folder 2)
      - Buildings-Schools & Colleges-New York City Public Schools- P.S. 165, W. 109th street (Box 81, Folder 3)
      - Buildings-Schools & Colleges-Parochial schools (Box 81, Folder 4)
      - Buildings-Schools & Colleges-Private schools-Miscellaneous (Box 81, Folder 5)
      - Buildings-Schools & Colleges-Private schools- Mrs. Semple's School (Box 81, Folder 6)
      - Buildings-Schools & Colleges-Medical schools-General (Box 81, Folder 7)
      - Buildings-Schools & Colleges-Medical schools-College of Physicians and Surgeons (Box 81, Folder 8)
      - Buildings-Schools & Colleges-Medical schools- Stuyvesant Institute, University Medical College (Box 81, Folder 9)
      - Buildings-Schools & Colleges-Professional and Trade schools (Box 81, Folder 10)
      - Buildings-Schools & Colleges-Theological Seminaries (Box 81, Folder 11)
      - Buildings-Schools & Colleges-City College of New York (previously Free Academy) (Box 82, Folder 1)
      - Buildings-Schools & Colleges-Columbia University (formerly King's College): Park Place (Box 82, Folder 2)
      - Buildings-Schools & Colleges-Columbia University (formerly King's College): E. 49th-50th Street (Box 82, Folder 3)
      - Buildings-Schools & Colleges-Columbia University (formerly King's College): Morningside Heights (Box 82, Folder 4-6)
      - Buildings-Schools & Colleges-Cooper Union (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - Buildings-Schools & Colleges-Hunter College (previously Normal College) (Box 83, Folder 2)
      - Buildings-Schools & Colleges-New York University, Washington Square (Box 83, Folder 3)
      - Buildings-Schools & Colleges-Rutgers Female College (Box 83, Folder 4)
      - Buildings-Schools & Colleges-Miscellaneous Colleges and Universities (Box 83, Folder 5-6)
      - Buildings-Sports Stadia and Stables (Box 83, Folder 7)
      - Buildings-Theaters-A-B miscellaneous (Box 83, Folder 8)
      - Buildings-Theaters-Academy of Music (Box 83, Folder 9)
      - Buildings-Theaters-Astor Place Opera House (Box 83, Folder 10)
      - Buildings-Theaters-Barnum's American Museum (SEE: Libraries and Museums)
      - Buildings-Theaters-Booth's Theater (Box 83, Folder 11)
      - Buildings-Theaters-Bowery Theater (Box 83, Folder 12)
      - Buildings-Theaters-Broadway Theater (Box 83, Folder 13)
      - Buildings-Theaters-C-D miscellaneous (Box 83, Folder 14)
      - Buildings-Theaters-Casino (Box 83, Folder 15)
      - Buildings-Theaters-Castle Garden (as Aquarium, SEE: Libraries and Museums. As Immigration Station, SEE: Government Buildings) (Box 83, Folder 16)
      - Buildings-Theaters-Chatham Theatre (Box 83, Folder 17)
      - Buildings-Theaters-E-F miscellaneous (Box 84, Folder 1)
      - Buildings-Theaters-G-H miscellaneous (Box 84, Folder 2)
      - Buildings-Theaters-Grand Opera House (Box 84, Folder 3)
      - Buildings-Theaters-Hippodrome (Box 84, Folder 4)
      - Buildings-Theaters-I-J miscellaneous (Box 84, Folder 5)
      - Buildings-Theaters-K-L miscellaneous (Box 84, Folder 6)
      - Buildings-Theaters-Lincoln Center (Box 84, Folder 7)